Robert Hare Papers 1764-1859 Mss.B.H22
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  Finally, there are a number of letters related to the business activities John Innes Clark of Providence, Rhode Island, all dated in the 1790s. Clark was the father of Hare’s wife Harriet. The correspondence deals mostly with issues related to Clark’s activities as a merchant. There is also some material about matters dealing with real estate transactions, and a few letters contain personal information.
  - [Samuel Powel?] Short notes on a course of Antiquities at Rome, In Company with Messrs. Apthorp, [John] Morgan and Palmer..., 1764; D. 1 vol.consisting of 36 leaves, bound with paper covers.; Powel, Samuel (1738-1793) (Box 1)
  - Clark and Nightingale. Agreement with carpenters..., 1787 May (Box 1)
    Agreement with carpenters, Jon[atha]n Hamon, John Smith and Andrew Cole, for the erection of a house in Providence. Draft.
  - Lydia Clark to Colonel Ward, 1790 January 1; Clark, Lydia (Box 1)
    L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Asks her to procure a looking lass for her when he goes to England.
  - Clark and Nightingale Specifications for work on a house, 1790? (Box 1)
  - Lydia Waterman to Lydia Clark, 1791 July 16 (Box 1)
    Sends yarn spun for her from flax. Asks to be paid for it.
  - Alexander Hosack. Receipt to John B. Murray, 1793 March 14 (Box 1)
  - John I. Clark? to John B. Murray, 1794 January 22 (Box 1)
    L. 4p. Draft. Concerning the settlement of an estate.
  - John Innes Clark to E. H. Robbins, 1794 Feb. 6 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Concerning the settlement of an estate.
  - John Innes Clark to John Ward, 1794 Feb. 6 (Box 1)
  - John Innes Clark to Page and Magee, 1794 Feb. 13 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Draft. Concerning investments for the triangular trade.
  - Clark and Nightingale to Colonel William Peck, 1794 Feb. 21 (Box 1)
    Providence L. 1p. and add., end.: "Copy of a letter..." Notifies him that he must move.
  - John Innes Clark to Richard Nicholls, 1794 March 6 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Draft. Business.
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1794 April 5 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p., end. Draft. Business. Settlement of an estate.
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1794 April 23 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 6p. and end. Draft. Various sizes. Business.
  - John Innes Clark to William Spooner, 1794 April 25 (Box 1)
    Providence, A.L.S. 1p. and end.: "Copy..." Sorry they will not purchase his property in Boston.
  - John Innes Clark to A. Hooper, 1794 Nov. 22 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p. Draft. Business. On same sheet is copy of letter from J. I. Clark to Mrs. A. Clark Hooper; Nov. 22, 1794.
  - John Innes Clark to A. Hooper, 1794 Nov. 22 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p., letter. On same sheet as copy of letter from J. I. Clark to A. Hooper; Nov. 22, 1794.
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1794 Dec. 18 (Box 1)
    Providence, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end.: "Copy.." Business. Concerning Murray's plans for his [Clark's] son.
  - John Innes Clark to Robert Murray, 1795 Aug. 4 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Business.
  - John Innes Clark to John Maclellan, 1796 Feb. 12 (Box 1)
  - John Innes Clark to Oliver Peabody, 1796 June 27 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Pays taxes on some lands.
  - John Innes Clark to Robert Murray, 1796 July 11 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p., end. Copy. Business.
  - John Innes Clark to Robert Murray, 1796 Aug. 2 (Box 1)
  - John Innes Clark to John Thurston, 1796 Aug. 22 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Stresses the honesty and integrity of some friends who are bankrupt.
  - John Innes Clark to Robert Murray, 1796 Aug. 22 (Box 1)
    L. 1p. and end. Copy. Business.
  - John Innes Clark and J. B. Murray to Robert Bird, 1796 Sept. 5 (Box 1)
    Providence, L.S. with initials: J. I. C[lark] and J. B. M[urray]. 1p. and end. Copy. Business.
  - John Innes Clark to John Thurston, 1796 Oct. 4 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Asks him to appear at court for Robett Murray.
  - John Innes Clark to Azur Archbald, 1796 Oct. 6 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Inquires for description of prints.
  - John Innes Clark Promissory note to William Jarvis, 1796 Nov. 1 (Box 1)
    Boston, D. 1p. and end. Draft. Note for agreements made by John B. Murray, etc.
  - Roux and Hill. Statement to Mr. Clark, 1796 Dec. 22 (Box 1)
    Charleston, L. 1p., and end. Mr. [John Innes] Clark for purchase of rum, brandy, etc.
  - John Innes Clark to Bird, Savage and Bird, 1796 Dec. 24 (Box 1)
    Charlestown, L. 2p. and end. Copy. Use of funds for relieving a specific house, that of Clark and Nightingale.
  - Rogers Barker and Lord. Account with Messrs. E. Bowen, Jr., Clark and Nightingale, 1797 Jan. 26 (Box 1)
    D. 3p. and end.
  - John Innes Clark to Lydia Clark, 1797 Feb. 9 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p. and end. Copy. Family news. Friendly letter.
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1797 Feb. 20 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Business matters are worsening.
  - John Innes Clark to Thomas Simmons, 1797 Feb. 25 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Cannot locate a washing machine for him. Thanks for his kindness while visiting.
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1797 March 4 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p. Copy. Glad he is going to Europe to help his brother. Plans for the care of his children.
  - John Innes Clark to Lydia Clark, 1797 March 14 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p., end. Copy. Hopes her trip is helping her. Family news.
  - Clark and Nightingale to Charles Murray, 1797 April 25 (Box 1)
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1797 May 4 (Box 1)
  - John Innes Clark to Lydia Clark, 1797 May 8 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 3p. and end. Copy. Hopes she receives the items sent her. News of trade.
  - John Innes Clark to John B. Murray, 1797 May 9 (Box 1)
  - Clark and Nightingale to Mr. William Jarvis, 1797 May 19 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Forwards note and agress to his plans for payments.
  - Clark and Nightingale to Captain Benjamin Page, 1797 May 29 (Box 1)
    L. 1p. and end. Will purchase tea from him.
  - John Innes Clark to Robert Murray, 1797 June 10 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p., end. Copy. Their chances on a law suit. Business matters.
  - John Innes Clark and J. B. Murray to William Cargill, 1797 July 10 (Box 1)
    Providence, L.S.: Jn. I. Clark for self & J. B. Murray. 1p. and end. Copy. Concerning the sale of lands.
  - John Innes Clark to Robert Murray, 1797 July 17 (Box 1)
  - John I. Clark to John B. Murray, 1797 Oct. 5 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 3p. and end. Copy. News of Robert Murray. Business. Friendly letter.
  - John Innes Clark to Mrs. John B. Murray, 1797 Oct. 8 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 2p., end. Copy. Asks her to hire a female servant for Mrs. Clark.
  - John Innes Clark to Lydia Clark, 1797 Oct. 22 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 3p. and end. Copy. Concerning her health. Family news. Hopes to see her in the spring.
  - Clark and Nightingale to ---, 1797 Nov. 4 (Box 1)
    Providence, L. 1p. and end. Copy. Death of Mr. Nightingale. Sale of the property of the firm must await further action.
  - Thomas Cole. Promissory note to John Innes Clark, 1797 Nov. 6 (Box 1)
    Providence, D.S. 1p. and end.
  - John Innes Clark to Jonathan Hastings, 1797 Nov. 9 (Box 1)
  - John Innes Clark. Receipt to John Clark Nightingale, 1797 Nov. 13 (Box 1)
    Providence, D. 1p. Copy.
  - John Innes Clark. Agreement with Jonathan Hastings, 1797 Nov. 14 (Box 1)
    D. 2p., end.
  - Philadelphia Citizens. Resolutions..., 1798 May 1 (Box 1)
    D. 2p. and end. Resolutions approving of the actions of John Adams as president of the United States.
  - Philadelphia Citizens to John Adams..., 1798 (Box 1)
    L. 2p. and end. Approves his actions as president.
  - Robert Murray to John Innes Clark, 1802 Sept. 25 (Box 1)
    Boston, L.S. with initials. 1p. and add. Business. Glad to hear Mrs. Clark is safely home.
  - John Prince to John I. Clark, 1803 June 30 (Box 1)
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Forwards "philosophical apparatus" etc. for the college and various persons.
  - Robert Hare. Verses addressed to Margaret Willing Hare, 1804 Jan. 15 (Box 1)
    [finished]. D.S. 2p. and end. For Mrs. Hare's birthday.
  - W. H. Blodget to Robert Hare, 1805 Feb. 21 (Box 1)
    St. Marks, A.L.S. with initials. 4p. News of his adventures on board ship and attempts at selling.
  - Robert Hare. Verses to Margaret Willing Hare, 1807 Jan. 15 (Box 1)
  - Robert Hare "Analysis of moral sentiments", 1808 May 7 (Box 1)
    D. 14p.
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    Printed: Port Folio, vol.XIX, [May 7, 1808], pp.295-300.
  - Robert Hare Verses to his wife Margaret Willing Hare, 1809 Jan. 15 (Box 1)
    D. 1p. and end.
  - Agreement concerning the John Innes Clark Estate, 1811 July 29 (Box 1)
    Concerning the John Innes Clark estate in Tennessee. D.S.: Lydia Clark and 5 others. On same sheet is letter from Josiah Nichol to Robert Hare; May 31, 1820.
  - Robert Hare to William Cooke, 1812 Feb. 26 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p. Draft. Concerning the estate of W. H. Blodget. On same sheet is copy of letter from Hare to William Cooke; March 3, 1812.
  - Robert Hare to William Cooke, 1812 March 3
    A.L. 1p. Draft. Concerning the estate of W. H. Blodget. On same sheet as copy of letter from Hare to Cooke; Feb. 26, 1812.
  - Hope and Co. to Robert Hare, 1814 May 9 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia; Amsterdam, L. 1p. Duplicate. Business.
  - Benjamin Silliman to William Meredith, 1815 Dec. 28 (Box 1)
    New Haven, A.L.S. 4p., add. Concerning the chair of chemistry at Penn and his recommendation of Hare for it.
  - Thomas Cadwalader to Robert Hare, 1818 May 25 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and edd., end. Cannot see Mr. Corbin. Concerning his appointment at Penn.
  - Josiah Nichol to Robert Hare, 1820 May 31 (Box 1)
    Nashville, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards material on the J. I. Clark estate in Tennessee. On same sheet with "Agreement concerning the John Innes Clark Estate," 1811 July 29.
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, 1820 August 29
    Regarding a publication.
  - Robert Hare to Granville Sharpe Pattison, 1820 Nov. 17 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Copy. Did not preserve his cousin's letter.
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, 1821 Jan. 20
    Is sending apparatus and a copy of his memoir.
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, 1821 Jan. 30
    Regarding engravings.
  - Robert Hare to Benjamin Silliman, 1821 Feb. 23
    Is planning to send apparatus. Did some experiments.
  - M. Hare to Robert Hare, 1821 June 6 (Box 1)
    Shrivenham, England, L. 4p. Family news. Distributed his scientific pamphlets. Quotes letter of Buckland about his invention of the gas blow-pipe.
  - Robert Hare to Parker Cleaveland, 1821 July 20 (Box 1)
    Providence, A.L.S. 4p., end. Copy. Describes his newly invented apparatus and tells him where to purchase the glass.
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1821 Dec. 19 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 1p. and add., end. Has drawn on him for $153.30.
  - Henry Gardiner to Robert Hare, 1822 March 2 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Possible sale of newly created varnish.
  - John Morgan. Shipping receipt to Robert Hare, 1822 March 18 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 1p. and end. Receipt to Robert Hare for shipment of minerals to A. Moquiart, La Havre, France.
  - John D'Wolf to Robert Hare, 1822 May 1 (Box 1)
    Providence, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Is glad he can purchase the chemical apparatus and wishes it shipped to Brown University.
  - Robert Hare to Elisha De Butts, 1822 June 9 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 3p. and end. Draft. Concerning their discussions on a matter for lecturing students and Dr. Physick's advice.
  - William J. Macneven to Robert Hare, 1823 March 28 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Lists his chemical apparatus, one item of which he acquired from Peale's museum.
  - Robert Hare to Jean Frédéric Daniel Lobstein, 1823 April 28 (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Draft. Apologizes for not having thanked him before now for the kind gift of his publication.
  - William W. Stewart to Robert Hare, 1823 May 14 (Box 1)
    Winchester, Tenn., A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Asks him to analyze some ores.
  - Robert Hare to Jullien de Paris, 1823 May 19 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and end. Draft. Wishes to correspond with him. Sends some publications on his inventions of apparatus, especially the gas blow-pipe.
  - Robert Hare to Louis Jacques Thenard, 1823 May 19 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p., end. Draft. Introduces himself and sends publications proving his priority in the invention of the gas blow-pipe.
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1823 Oct. 6 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 1p. and add., end. Cannot fill his order immediately and cannot quite prices.
  - Robert Hare to John Markoe, 1823 Nov. (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Draft. Ready to pay ground-rent.
  - Mrs. Lenox to Robert Hare, 1824 July 29 (Box 1)
    Bristol, Pennsylvania. A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. and add., end. Concerning a servant.
  - Robert Hare to Major Lenox, 1824 July 31 (Box 1)
    Regarding a servant who had made application. Response to letter of July 29.
  - Badge worn...in honor of La Fayette, 1824 Sept. 28 (Box 1)
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1824 Oct. 20 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 1p. and add., end. His order is not yet completed for his apparatus.
  - John and Richard Fisher. Receipt for shipment of materials to Robert Hare, 1824 Oct. 25 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 2p. and receipt for shipment for material to Dr. Hare, and add., end. Material for his chemical apparatus.
  - E. Campbell to Harriet Clark Hare, 1824 Oct. 27 (Box 1)
    Williamsburg, A.L.S. 2p. and add. News of the college and town.
  - William Coxe to Robert Hare, 1824 Nov. 10 (Box 1)
    Burlington, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Ships cider.
  - William Channing Woodbridge to Robert Hare, 1824 Dec. 2 (Box 1)
    Liverpool, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Signature mutilated. Has arrived safely and proposes to visit London and then the Continent.
  - J. B. Quinby to Robert Hare, 1824 Dec. 18 (Box 1)
    Boston, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Concerning the idea of using coal to make iron.
  - Samuel Brown to Robert Hare, 1825 Jan. 15 (Box 1)
    Lexington, A.L.S. 6p. and add. Proposes study of the human body to see if electrical properties might not account for various organs functioning the way they do.
  - Peter Falinestock to Robert Hare, 1825 Jan. 15 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Is student, faces financial difficulties, asks refund for the unused portion of his tickets.
  - American Sunday School Union. Receipt to Robert Hare, 1825 May 19 (Box 1)
    D. 1p. and end. For life membership.
  - M. Hare to Robert Hare, 1825 July 20 (Box 1)
    Shrivenham, England, A.L.S. 4p., and., end. From his aunt. Is proud of his and all he has accomplished.
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1825 Aug. 13 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 2p. and add., end. Plant is being enlarged but will be in operation within 6 weeks.
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1825 Sept. 10 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 1p. and add., end. Need his drawings in order to execute his order.
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1825 Sept. 28 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 1p. and add. end. Will begin making his chemical apparatus about Oct. 4.
  - John and Richard Fisher to Robert Hare, 1825 Oct. 31 (Box 1)
    New York, L. 1p. and add., end. Working on his chemical apparatus.
  - J. and R. Fisher. Shipping receipt to Robert Hare, 1825 Nov. 12 (Box 1)
    New York, Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and list of chemical apparatus on same sheet.
  - James De Groot. Receipt to Robert Hare, 1826 March 17 (Box 1)
    A.D.S. 1p.
  - Benjamin Silliman to Robert Hare, 1826 May 11 (Box 1)
    New Haven, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Concerning his article on the blowpipe.
  - Harriet Clark Hare to Bishop Chase, 1827 Feb. 28 (Box 1)
    Philadelphia, L. in hand of Robert Hare(?). 3p. and end. Draft. Gift of monies to the school from her mother (Mrs. Lydia Clark).
  - Robert Hare. Account of student fees..., 1827 Aug. - 1831 Feb. (Box 1)
  - James P. Wilson to Robert Hare, 1828 Dec. 25; Wilson, James P.(James Patriot),1769-1830. (Box 1)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Critical remarks on his publication on chemistry.
  - Robert Hare to Dr. Wilson, 1828 Dec. 31 (Box 1)
    A.L. 4p. Draft. Also, draft in different version. 3p. and end. Concerning his publication on chemistry.
  - M. Hare to Robert Hare, 1829 April 21 (Box 1)
    Shrivenham, England, A.L.S. 4p., add. From his aunt. Thanks for publication. Her medical lore. Friendly letter.
  - L. D. Gale to Robert Hare, 1831 Jan. 24; Gale, Leonard Dunnell, 1800-1883 (Box 2)
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Seal. Chemical experiments.
  - Benjamin Silliman to Robert Hare, 1832 April 4 (Box 2)
    New Haven, A.L.S. 2p., end. and add. Concerning publications concerning Hare and some of his experiments.
  - Robert Hare to Mr. Pillow, 1832 Aug. 20 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. and add. and end. Complains of a servant.
  - P. J. Uylenbroek to Robert Hare, 1833 Dec. 21; Uylenbroek, Petrus Johannes (Box 2)
    L. 1p. and end. In Latin. Proposes exchange of publications with the APS and the Rijksuniversiteit of Leyden.
  - Samuel Haydock to Robert Hare, 1834 Sept. 1 (Box 2)
  - Robert Hare to Samuel Haydock, 1834 Sept. (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Draft. Attempts an explanation for the collapse of a copper vessel.
  - Samuel Haydrock to Robert Hare, 1834 Nov. 1
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Asks explanation for collapse of a copper vessel used as water cooler.
  - Sev Lorig to Robert Hare, 1834 Nov. 25 (Box 2)
    New York, L. 2p. and add., end. Concerning the shipment of publications and letters. Refers to the APS and Berzelius.
  - Robert Hare to Johan Jakob Berzelius, 1835 July 20 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L. 3p. and end. Copy. ----Copy. Mutilated. 16x10. Chemical subjects. Refers to Silliman.
  - J. S. Rose to Robert Hare, 1835 Dec. 8 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Effects of electricity on diseases.
  - Robert Hare. Statement of sums paid to the Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania by the medical faculty, ca.1835? (Box 2)
    A.D. 1p. and end. Draft.
  - Jonas Humbert, Jr. to Robert Hare, 1836 Feb.12; Humbert, Jonas, 1784-1849 (Box 2)
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Asks him if he would perform an experiment using electricity, hydrogen, and oxygen.
  - Franklin Bache. List of APS Members in Europe, 1836 April 21 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p. and end. Addressed to Dr. Hare. List of American Philosophical Society members in Europe, not known to be living or dead. Asks Hare to see if such people are still alive, while he is in Europe.
  - Robert Hare to Alexander Dallas Bache, 1836 April 25 (Box 2)
    L. 1p. and end. Copy. Asks him to correct errors in a new edition of his text-book.
  - Lewis C. Beck to Robert Hare, 1836 April 29; Beck, Lewis C. (Lewis Caleb), 1798-1853 (Box 2)
    New Brunswick, A.L.S. 4p. Describes a tornado.
  - J. Bostock to Robert Hare, 1836 July 30; Bostock, John, 1773-1846 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 2p. Cannot ask him to visit, since the house is being painted, but hopes to see him anyhow.
  - A. Stevenson to Robert Hare, 1836 Aug. 10; Stevenson, Alan, 1807-1865 (Box 2)
    L. 2p. Has obtained permission for him to sit in either the House of Commons or the Galleries there.
  - Robert Hare to Messrs. Enderby, 1836 Aug. 14 (Box 2)
    Windsor, England, A.L.S. 1p. end end. Copy. Orders chemical.
  - Martha Hare to Robert Hare, 1836 Sept. 29 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning the Hare family.
  - U. of Virginia. Report on R. H. Hare..., 1836 Dec. 1 (Box 2)
  - Charles Daubeny to Robert Hare, 1836 Dec. 16 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 4p., add., end. Concerning the British Association for the Advancement of Science. Friendly letter.
  - U. of Virginia. Report on R. H. Hare..., 1837 Jan. 1 (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and add., end.
  - J. Purcell to Robert Hare, 1837 Feb. 15 (Box 2)
    Lancaster, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Has discovered a sovereign remedy for poisons and wishes to set up agents in the U.S. for the sale of it. Asks his advice.
  - U. of Virginia. Report on R. H. Hare..., 1837 March 1 (Box 2)
  - Stephen P. Morris to Robert Hare, 1837 March 2; Morris, Stephen P. (Stephen Paschall), 1800-1865 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Asks questions concerning the making of iron.
  - U. of Virginia. Report on R. H. Hare..., 1837 April 1 (Box 2)
  - U. of Virginia. Report on R. H. Hare..., 1837 May 1 (Box 2)
  - W. M. Meredith to Robert Hare, 1838 July 17; Meredith, William M. (William Morris), 1799-1873 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Forwards check from Otis Allen.
  - William Sullivan to Robert Hare, 1838 Aug. 6; Sullivan, William, 1774-1839 (Box 2)
    Newport, R.I., A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Concerning education. Friendly letter.
  - Samuel Webb to Robert Hare, 1838 Nov. 29 (Box 2)
    L.S. 1p. and add. Asks him to accept a history of the Pennsylvania Hall, since part of it is dedicated to the Indians.
    General note
    Freeman Guide 1492.
  - Thomas Senturner to Robert Hare, 1839 June 18 (Box 2)
    Hameln, L.S. 2p. and add., end. In German. Thanks for publication. Concerning publication of Liebig. Friendly letter.
  - Robert Hare. Concerning boilers and steam-boats, 1839? (Box 2)
    A.D. 4p. and end. Various sizes.
  - Pass to Mr. Droop and Friends..., 1840 June (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. Pass for the St. Katharine Docks, London.
  - John R. Alexander to Miss Hare, 1840 July 20; Alexander, John, 1792-1868 (Box 2)
    Ryde England, A.L.S. 2p. and P.S. by [John Innes Clark Hare?]. Wishes they could be together. Family speaks of her.
  - Sally E. Hare. Power of attorney to Robert Hare, 1841 March 30 (Box 2)
    D.S. 1p. Witnessed: I.P.Hutchinson and Robert Harford Hare.
  - M. Hare to Robert Hare, 1841 April 9 (Box 2)
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p., add. Death of Harrison and acts of Tyler. Friendly letter.
  - Miss Hare to Robert Hare, 1841 April 30 (Box 2)
    A.L.S.: Your affectionate, Daughter, 4p., add. Friendly letter of family and friends.
  - Petty Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 May 6; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854 (Box 2)
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 2p. and add. Reminds him of an engagement to take tea with him.
  - Petty Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 May 6; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 3p. Will introduce him to the Zoological Society on Tuesday evening.
  - A.P. Gibson to Robert Hare, 1841 May 7 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. Informs him of how to board a particular vessel.
  - William Vaughan. Ticket of admission..., 1841 May 7; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850 (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 1p. Ticket of admission to the Royal Institution for Robert Hare.
  - Petty Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 May 7; Vaughan, Petty, 1788-1854 (Box 2)
    A.L.S. 3p. Friendly letter. Hopes to provide him with tickets to a fete.
  - William Vaughan. Pass..., 1841 May 7; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850 (Box 2)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 1p. Ticket of admission to the Royal Institution for Robert Harford Hare.
  - Sir Thomas Dyke Acland to Robert Hare, [1841] May 10; Acland, Thomas Dyke, Sir, 1787-1871 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 4p. Hopes to meet and tries to get a seat for him in Commons.
  - William Vaughan to Robert Hare, 1841 May 12; Vaughan, William, 1752-1850 (Box 2)
    L.S. 1p. Invites him to tea.
  - M. Wellesley to Robert Hare, [1841] May 12 (Box 4)
    A.L.S. 2p. Hopes to see him when he returns to town next week.
  - Robert Addams to Robert Hare, [1841] May 13 (Box 4)
    Kensington [London], A.L.S. 2p. Concerning his chemical apparatus. Says Faraday uses it.